Do you realize this is the last time we'll be here...
你們知道這是最後一次 我們以六個單身朋友的身份…
as six single people?
共聚一堂嗎？
What's happening to the coffeehouse?
咖啡廳怎麼了？
From now on, it's you four and me and the missus.
從現在開始，是你們四個好朋友 我跟我太太了
The little woman. The wife. The old ball and chain.
我的小女人，好老婆 老的繫絆
-Old? -The young, hot ball and chain.
-老的？ -你是年輕性感的繫絆
-Much better. -We gotta go.
-好多了 -我們得走了
-Where? -Get the dress and lunch with mom.
-去哪裡？ -我要去拿婚紗，跟媽媽一起吃午餐
Joey, you too?
喬伊，你也要去？
I just heard "lunch."
我聽到了「午餐」
Yeah, I can go. Sure.
對，我可以去，當然
Actually, I'm glad they're leaving.
事實上我很高興他們離開了
I need to talk to you about something.
有件事我得跟你談一談
-What's up? -This may be a little awkward.
-什麼事？ -這或許會有點嚇人
If you need money, it's a bad time. I'm buying 128 dinners tomorrow.
如果你需要錢，時機真的不太對 明天晚上我得請一百二十八個人吃晚餐
No, it's not that.
不，不是那樣的
I'm not gonna say this as your friend...
我不是以你朋友的身份 跟你說話…
but as Monica's older brother.
我要以摩妮卡大哥的身份跟你談
-But you're still my friend? -Not for a few minutes.
-但你還是我朋友吧？ -接下來的幾分鐘不是
-Right now, are you still my best man? -No.
-現在你還是我的伴郎嗎？ -不是
Do I still call you Ross?
我還是可以叫你羅斯嗎？
You guys are getting married, and I couldn't be more thrilled.
你們要結婚了，我真的很高興
But as her older brother, I have to tell you this:
但身為她的大哥 我得告訴你一件事
If you ever hurt my little sister...
如果你敢傷害我妹妹…
if you ever cause her any unhappiness of any kind...
如果你敢讓她不快樂…
I will hunt you down...
天涯海角我都會找到你…
and kick your ass.
我會痛扁你
What? I'm serious.
什麼？我是認真的
-Dude! Stop it! I'm not kidding. -I hear what you're saying...
-兄弟，別鬧了，我不是在開玩笑 -我聽到你的話了…
and thanks for the warning.
謝謝你的警告
No problem.
別客氣
Are we friends again?
我們又是朋友了？
Yeah.
對
You won't believe what Monica's brother just said to me!
你不會相信剛剛摩妮卡的 哥哥跟我說了什麼！
The One With Monica and Chandler's Wedding
摩妮卡和錢德的婚禮上集
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
What you doing, Mon?
你在做什麼？摩妮卡
I'm listing things that could go wrong at the wedding.
我在列出 婚禮上可能會出差錯的事情
So I can be prepared.
那樣子我可以做好準備
-What are they? -"The dresses won't get picked up...
-哪些事會出差錯？ -到目前為止有婚紗忘了拿…
veil gets lost, and I'm missing something blue."
我的頭紗不見了 或是我忘了拿藍色的東西
I'm responsible for all those.
那是我負責的事
I had to go with the odds.
我得做好萬全準備
Remember I didn't get that part?
你們還記得之前我去試鏡 沒有拿到那個角色的事嗎？
-The commercial? -That play?
-那個廣告？ -那出舞台劇？
That other play?
另一出舞台劇？
-The movie? -Yes!
-那部電影？ -對
The one about the dog who flies planes?
那部狗會開飛機的電影？
No. But man, that one hurt.
不，但我真的很傷心
-This is the one about WWI soldiers. -Oh, yeah.
-這部電影在描述一次大戰的士兵 -喔，對
Back then we called it "The Great War."
以前我們叫它「大戰」
It really was.
它真的是大戰
A guy they wanted backed out! I start shooting today!
他們錄取的那個角色不演了！ 我今天就要開始拍戲！
Congratulations!
恭喜！
-Today's the dinner. -I'll be done by then.
-今天有綵排晚宴 -我一定會趕過去的
Oh. Then way to go, you big movie star!
喔，那麼太棒了 你成了電影明星！
See you. I'm off to fight the Nazis.
待會見，我要去跟納粹作戰了
Wait, Joey. We fought the Nazis in WWII, not WWI.
等一下，喬伊，納粹是我們 在二次大戰的敵人，不是一次大戰
Whoa.
Who was in WWI?
誰是我們在一次大戰的敵人？
Go ahead.
你說吧
You're gonna be late! Go! Go!
你要遲到了！快去…
Who did we fight in WWI?
誰是我們在一次大戰的敵人？
-Mexico? -Yes. Very good.
-墨西哥？ -對，非常棒
（五十九號碼頭片廠）
-Hey, Joey. We're ready. -Yeah, me too.
-嘿，喬伊，我們準備好了 -我也是
Richard, we're ready for you.
理查，我們準備好了
Joey Tribbiani, Richard Crosby is playing Vincent.
喬伊崔比亞尼，這位是理查克洛斯比 他要飾演文森
-I'm acting with you? -Nice to meet you.
-我要跟你演對手戲？ -很高興能認識你
I can't believe this. Incredible. You just won an Oscar.
我不敢相信，這太不可思議了 你剛剛拿下奧斯卡金像獎
No, I didn't.
不，我沒有
I think you did.
我知道你有
I think I lost, three times.
我想三次我都輸了
-Cookie? Would you...? -No.
-餅乾？你要…？ -不
We're about an hour away from getting the scene lit.
再過一小時我們就要正式開拍
-Can you guys run it a couple times? -Yeah, sure.
-你們能對一下戲嗎？ -沒問題
All right. Let's do it.
好了，我們開始吧
And... action!
好了…開始！
-We have to find the platoon! -Forget it, the platoon is gone!
-我們得找到其他士兵！ -算了吧，他們已經不在了！
-What? -Platoon's dead! Face facts, Tony!
-什麼？ -他們都死了！面對現實吧，東尼！
What'll we do? We have no reinforcements or food.
我們該怎麼辦？ 我們沒有援兵或食物
There's food in the basement. Potatoes and some pasta.
地下室有食物 有馬鈴薯跟一些意大利面
Hang on. Joey, you keep touching your face.
等一下，喬伊，你一直在摸你的臉
Something wrong?
有什麼問題嗎？
No.
不，沒有
I thought it might be a cool character thing.
我以為這麼做會很酷
He's a face toucher.
他是個喜歡摸臉的人
I don't think so.
我可不那麼認為
Let's take it back to Richard's last lines. Action!
我們從理查 最後一句台詞開始，開始！
No weapons, but we still have food.
雖然我們沒有武器 但我們還有食物
Potatoes, pasta...
馬鈴薯，意大利面…
and a few tins of tuna!
跟幾罐鮪魚
Honey, we gotta go!
甜心，我們得走了！
Here's a question you never want to ask:
這個問題真的很難啟齒
Can my dad borrow one of your pearl necklaces?
我爸能借用你的珍珠項鏈嗎？
Did he say what kind of neckline he's wearing?
他有提到 他的領口剪裁是哪一種的嗎？
No.
沒有
I just met him once, but I'm guessing...
我只見過他一次但我猜…
plunging?
是低胸的？
He is more of a if-you've-got-it- flaunt-it kind of father.
他是那種不嚇死人不罷休的爸爸
Let me see if Rachel has anything.
我去問問瑞秋有沒有適合的項鏈
Yes, include more people.
對，把更多的人扯進來
Do you realize that tomorrow we're gonna be getting married?
你知道明天這個時候 我們要結婚嗎？
I have a date tomorrow night.
我明天晚上有約了
-I can't believe we made it. -Don't sound so surprised.
-我不敢相信我們真的辦到了 -別一副很訝異的樣子
I'm sorry, but...
對不起，但是…
-Nothing. -What?
-沒事 -什麼？
Well, honestly? Ever since we got engaged...
喔，真的嗎？自從我們訂婚後…
I've waited for you to flip out.
我一直在期待 發生什麼事讓你退縮
Honestly? Me too.
真的嗎？我也是
-Really? -Yeah.
-真的嗎？ -對
I think that something will come up and I'll...
我以為會發生什麼事 然後我會作…
go all Chandler.
錢德會作的事
-But nothing has. -I'm so glad.
-但什麼事都沒發生 -我很高興
Thank you for staying so calm during this.
謝謝你在這段時間 一直都非常地冷靜
It's made me stay calm.
它讓我非常地冷靜
I could've been worse.
我可能會更差的
I'll be right there.
我馬上回來
Before Saturday, you've reached Monica and Chandler.
如果你在星期六前打電話來 這裡是摩妮卡跟錢德家
But if you're calling after Saturday, you've reached Mr. and Mrs. Bing.
但如果你在星期六後打電話來 這裡是賓氏夫婦家
Please leave a message for... the Bings!
請留話給…賓氏夫婦！
Maureen!
嘿，墨琳！
-This is my cousin, Maureen. -We're the Bings.
-她是我表妹墨琳 -我們是賓氏夫婦
Hi! You guys look so beautiful.
嗨，你們都很漂亮
Mr. and Mrs. Bing!
賓先生跟賓太太
Wow, Monica.
摩妮卡
So you know, I had my older-brother talk with Chandler.
你知道的，我以 「大哥的身份」跟錢德談過
What is that?
你說了什麼？
I told him that if he ever hurt you...
我告訴他如果他敢傷害你…
I would hunt him down and kick his ass.
天涯海角我都會找到他 痛扁他
What is the matter with everybody? I'm serious.
大家是怎麼了？我是認真的
I would kick his ass!
我會痛扁他！
Ross, please, my makeup!
羅斯，拜託，我的妝要糊掉了！
-Chandler. -Mom.
-錢德 -媽
Thanks for wearing... something.
謝謝你記得穿…衣服來
This is so exciting! I thought we screwed you up too much for this.
我真的很興奮 我以為我們害得你不敢結婚
Just think, soon there will be lots of little Bings.
你想想，很快地 就會出現很多賓氏小孩
I can't believe I'm going back to get spit on again.
我不敢相信我要回去 讓人家噴口水
You're lucky, the people who spit on you are famous.
你很幸運 至少噴你口水的人都很有名
-Who spits on you? -I don't want to talk about work.
-誰對你噴口水？ -我不想談工作的事
Mrs. Bing? These are my parents, Judy and Jack Geller.
賓太太？他們是我爸媽 茱蒂跟傑克蓋勒
-It's lovely to meet you. -Are you his mother or father?
-很高興能見到你 -你是他媽媽還是他爸爸？
Jack!
傑克！
What? I've never seen one before.
什麼？我沒看過變性人
Dad, there's Ross. Go talk to him.
爸，羅斯在那邊 去跟他談一談吧
I wasn't even able to act like I'm okay with it.
我甚至沒辦法 假裝我不會在意
Hello, all.
大家好
Hi... Dad.
嗨…爸爸
Hi, Mr. Bing.
嗨，賓先生
-Nora. -Charles.
-諾拉 -查爾斯
-It's so great to see you both here. -Yes.
-很高興你們兩個都來了 -對
Although we may be seeing too much of some people.
雖然有些人是衣不蔽體
Aren't you too old to wear a dress like that?
你不覺得自己太老了 不該穿那種衣服嗎？
Don't you have too much penis to wear a dress like that?
你不覺得自己是個男人 不該穿那種衣服嗎？
Oh, my God.
喔，我的天啊
Of course you can kick his ass, son.
你當然可以痛扁他，兒子
You could kick anyone's ass you want to.
你想痛扁任何人都沒有問題
Thanks, you guys.
謝謝你們
-Rach, Rach? -Yeah?
-瑞秋？ -什麼？
Talk to Chandler's dad and keep him away from Chandler's mom.
快去跟錢德的爸聊天 別讓他跟錢德的媽媽槓上了
-What's he look like? -A man in a black dress.
-但我不知道他長什麼樣子 -他穿著黑色洋裝
I'm Rachel, a friend of Monica and Chandler's.
嗨，我是瑞秋 摩妮卡跟錢德的朋友
-I'm Amanda. -Oh, I get it.
-我是亞曼達 -喔，我懂了
"A man, duh!"
「男人，啊！」
Could I have your attention?
請大家聽我說
-I'm Ross Geller. -Dr. Ross Geller.
-我是羅斯蓋勒 -羅斯蓋勒博士
Dad, please. As I was saying...
爸，拜託，我剛剛說過…
I'm Dr. Ross Geller.
我是羅斯蓋勒博士
And I'm the best man.
我是伴郎
This marriage is doubly special for me...
這段婚姻對我來說有雙重意義…
because not only is the groom my best friend...
不只因為新郎是我的好朋友…
but the bride is my little sister.
更因為新娘是我的妹妹
She's the greatest sister a guy could ask for.
她是所有男人 夢寐以求的好妹妹
Please join me in raising a glass...
請大家跟我一起舉杯…
to the couple we're here to celebrate.
敬這對新人
-To the Bings. -To the Bings!
-敬賓氏夫婦 -敬賓氏夫婦！
I'm gonna steam my dress.
我要去熨婚紗了
Who will make sure nothing happens to it?
誰負責確定它不會有問題？
-I'll do it. -Who wants it? Anybody?
-我會負責 -誰要負責？有人願意嗎？
-I said I'll do it. -Nobody?
-我說我會負責 -沒有人嗎？
-All right, I'll do it myself. -I'm not gonna screw it up.
-好吧，那麼我就自己來 -我不會搞砸的
You're right. I'm sorry. You were a big help tonight.
你說的對，對不起 今晚你幫了大忙
Thanks for helping my grandmother get to the hotel.
謝謝你幫忙 將我奶奶安全地送回飯店
-Of course! That's what I'm here for. -Okay. Sorry.
-當然，那就是我的工作 -好吧，對不起
What grandmother?
什麼奶奶？
-Where have you been? -Taking my parents to the hotel.
-你跑到哪裡去了？ -我送我爸媽回飯店
-Going back to work? -Yeah.
-你要回去工作了？ -對
-Nice shades. -If I wear these in my scenes...
-很酷的太陽眼鏡 -我想如果我能戴上它拍戲
I won't get spit in my eyes.
我的眼睛就不會噴到口水了
And, if I remember correctly, Ray-Ban was the official sponsor of WWI.
如果我沒有記錯 雷朋是一次大戰的正式贊助商
Great! All right!
太棒了！帥啊！
I'll see you later.
-待會見 -好吧
-Where's Chandler? -I think he's in Rachel's room.
-錢德在哪裡？ -我想他在瑞秋的房間裡
Chandler?
錢德？
-Is Monica here? -She's steaming her dress. Why?
-摩妮卡在嗎？ -她在熨婚紗，怎麼了？
-I think Chandler's gone. -What?
-我想錢德走了 -什麼？
-He left that. -"Tell Monica I'm sorry."
-他留下了這個 -「告訴摩妮卡我很抱歉」
Oh, my God.
喔，我的天啊
What's up?
怎麼了？
"Tell Monica I'm sorry."
「告訴摩妮卡我很抱歉」
Tell her yourself.
你自己去告訴她
Oh, my God. Chandler just left, though?
喔，我的天啊，錢德走了？
Maybe it's not what we think.
或許事情不是我們想的那樣 或許他是說：
"Tell Monica I'm sorry I drank the last of the milk."
「告訴摩妮卡我很抱歉 我把牛奶都喝光了」
Or maybe he was writing to tell her that he's changed his name:
或許他寫這張字條告訴她 他改了名字
"Tell Monica, I'm Sorry."
「告訴摩妮卡我叫抱歉」
-It means he freaked out and left! -Don't be so negative!
-這表示他嚇得逃跑了！ -別那麼消極！
Good God, isn't it possible that "Sorry" is sitting in there right now?
天啊，有沒有可能「抱歉」 現在就坐在裡面
Phoebe, I think Ross is right. What are we gonna do?
菲比，我想羅斯說的對 我們該怎麼辦？
I'm gonna have to go find him and bring him back.
我得去找他，把他帶回來
You make sure Monica does not find out, okay?
你們別讓摩妮卡 發現這件事，好嗎？
But, if you don't find him and bring him back...
如果你沒辦法找到他 把他帶回來…
I am gonna hunt you down and kick your ass!
天涯海角我都會找到你 痛扁你！
I will find him.
我會找到他的
Joey? Can you go through these lines with me?
喬伊，你能跟我對一下台詞嗎？
Oh, man, they just re-did my makeup.
喔，天啊，他們才幫我補好妝
-Just the last two pages. -All right.
-只要對最後兩頁 -好吧
I found the picture!
我發現照片了！
Picture? What picture?
照片？什麼照片？
The picture of my wife I found in your pack.
我在你的背包裡 發現了我太太的照片
-Could you lower the script? -I don't want to.
-你能把劇本放下來嗎？ -我不想
I need to see your face so I can play off your reaction.
我得看到你的臉 才能知道你的反應
Okay, look.
好吧，聽我說
I know you're great and play all those Shakespeare guys...
我知道你的演技很棒 演過很多莎翁名劇…
but you're spitting all over me, man.
但你噴得我滿臉是口水
-Of course I am! -You know you've been spitting?
-那當然！ -你知道你會噴口水？
That's what real actors do.
真正的演員都會那麼做
Enunciation is the mark of a good actor.
發音是好演員的註冊商標
And when you enunciate, you spit!
發音正確時就會噴口水！
Wow. Didn't know that.
我不知道這件事
Thanks. Okay, check it out.
謝了，好吧，看我的
Picture? What picture?
照片？什麼照片？
-Have you seen Chandler? -No, I haven't seen him.
-阿甘，你看到錢德了嗎？ -不，我沒有看到他
-Damn. -He's getting married tomorrow, right?
-該死 -他明天要結婚了，對吧？
Yes. Don't worry. Everything's fine.
對，別擔心，一切都會沒事的
-See you at the wedding. -I wasn't invited.
-明天婚禮上見 -我沒有被邀請
Then we'll see you the day after tomorrow.
那麼後天見
Mom? Dad?
媽？爸？
What are you doing here?
你在這裡做什麼？
We thought we'd see what the fuss is all about.
我們想看看 這裡到底有什麼特別的
-I see why the girls like coming here. -Why?
-我知道為什麼女孩們喜歡來這裡 -為什麼？
The sexy blond behind the counter.
為了吧檯後面那個性感大帥哥
-Gunther? -She just added him to her list.
-阿甘？ -她剛剛把他列入她的名單
-Your list? -Of people we're allowed to sleep..
-什麼？你的名單？ -我們可以上床的對象…
I know what the list is.
我知道那是什麼樣的名單
Come on, sit down. Have a cup of joe.
快坐下吧，喝杯咖啡
Dad, I can't. I'm sorry.
爸爸，我沒空，抱歉
If you see Chandler, tell him I'm looking for him.
如果你看到錢德 告訴他我在找他
And if you see Rita Moreno, let her know I'm looking for her.
如果你看到麗塔莫雷諾 告訴她我在找她
Action!
開始！
I found the picture!
我發現照片了！
What picture?
什麼照片？
A picture of my wife, in your pack!
我在你的背包裡發現了我太太的照片
You went through my personal property?
你偷翻我的私人物品？
Why do you have a picture of Paulette in your pack?
你的背包裡 為什麼會有寶麗蒂的照片？
Because, Vincent, we were lovers...
文森，因為我們交往過…
for two years!
...兩年！
Cut! Wonderful!
卡！太棒了！
Great scene, huh?
真的是太棒了！
You were awesome. In that last speech, you soaked me.
你真的很棒 最後那一段你噴得我的臉都濕了
-Tomorrow's call sheet. -I'm not working tomorrow.
-這是明天的通告表 -明天我不會工作
-You are now. -No, you gotta get me out of it.
-現在是了 -不，你得幫我這個忙
I have plans. Important plans!
我已經有約了，這件事非常重要！
-Still no word from Chandler. -Oh, man.
-羅斯說還是沒有錢德的消息 -喔，天啊
But they found the grandmother wandering down 5th.
但他們發現 奶奶在第五大道上遊蕩
Okay, well there's one down.
好吧，至少找到一個人了
I'm getting married today!
今天我要結婚了
I cracked a rib, but I don't care. Today's my wedding!
我斷了一根肋骨，但我不在乎 今天我要結婚了！
My day is finally here!
我終於要結婚了！
She might not even notice he's gone.
或許她不會注意到他不見了
I'm gonna start getting ready!
我要開始準備了！
We can't let her start getting ready. This is too awful!
我們不能讓她開始準備 這太可怕了！
She'll be in the gown, and he won't show up.
但等她換上婚紗 而他又沒有出現時…
Then she'll have to take off the gown..
這時候她得脫掉婚紗…
Stop it. You can't do this here.
冷靜點，你不能在這裡抓狂
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
對不起，抱歉
It's just so sad.
那真的是太悲傷了
Pull it together. She can't see you like this.
振作一點 別讓她看到你這個樣子
-She'll know something's wrong. -I know. I know.
-她會發現不對勁的 -我知道，天啊！
There's no tissue.
沒有面紙了
Can you grab me some toilet paper?
你能拿張衛生紙給我嗎？
Oh, that's gone too. This is Monica's bathroom, right?
喔，衛生紙也沒有了 這裡是摩妮卡的浴室吧？
I found one.
-我找到一張了 -好吧
Thank you.
-拿去吧 -謝謝
Oh, God.
喔，天啊
Can I have another one?
能再給我一張嗎？
Sure.
沒問題
Do you need some floss?
你需要牙線嗎？
I can't imagine what will happen if he doesn't show up.
我無法想像如果他不出現 會發生什麼事
Here's a whole bunch.
這裡有一大堆衛生紙
She'll be at the wedding waiting...
她會在禮堂等他…
and people will be whispering, "That poor girl."
大家會竊竊竊竊私語 「喔，那個可憐的女孩」
Then she'll have to come back here and live alone.
然後她得回來這裡 獨自一個人過生活
-Oh, my God. -What?
-喔，我的天啊 -什麼？
There was a pregnancy test in the garbage, and it's positive.
垃圾桶有一根驗孕棒 是陽性反應
Monica's pregnant.
摩妮卡懷孕了
So I guess she won't be totally alone.
我猜她不會寂寞了
Next time on Friends:
下集提要
-We've gotta tell her. -No, we can't.
-我們得告訴她他失蹤了 -不，我們不能那麼做
She's getting ready.
她很快就會開始做準備
Can't you stall her?
你不能拖延她嗎？
I'm never gonna get married.
我永遠都沒辦法結婚了！
We've just got one scene with you two, and Richard is a pro.
我們只要拍一場戲 就你跟理查，他是職業高手
-Are you drunk? -No!
-你喝醉了嗎？ -沒有
Yes, you are!
你喝醉了！
All right.
好吧
-How's Chandler? -Great!
-錢德還好嗎？ -他好極了
-Where are you? -On the set.
-你在哪裡？ -我還在片場裡
It's turning into the worst wedding ever.
這將會是有史以來 最糟糕的一場婚禮